Guide to the Arts at Duke Reference Collection, circa 1910-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Arts at Duke Reference collection circa 1910-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
0.7 linear feet Extent: approx. 350 Items
The Arts at Duke Reference Collection contains files of clippings, programs, calendars and other materials concerning the arts at Duke and at Trinity College, the University's predecessor. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. For materials pertaining to art at Trinity College, see the Trinity College Reference Collection.
UA.01.11.0066
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Arts at Duke Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Collection Overview
The Arts at Duke Reference Collection contains files of clippings, programs, calendars and other materials concerning the arts at Duke and at Trinity College, the University's predecessor. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. For materials pertaining to art at Trinity College, see the Trinity College Reference Collection.
Flyers and posters, newspaper and magazine clippings, calendars, event programs and other materials pertaining to the arts at Duke and Trinity College. The bulk dates are 1972-2000. Includes a plan of the Woodland Stage at Trinity College along with programs and contracts for performances at Trinity by the Ben Greet Players and the Coburn Players, circa 1910-1916.
Subject Headings
Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Ben Greet Players; Coburn Players
Related Material
Departments and Academic Divisions reference collection
Duke University Archives
Department of Music records
Duke University Archives
Institute of the Arts records, 1981-[ongoing]
Duke University Archives
Woman's College Library records, 1930-1994 (bulk 1930-1970)
Duke University Archives
Arts Council records, 1950-1970 (bulk 1950-1959)
Duke University Archives
Duke University Museum of Art reference collection
Duke University Archives
Art Association records, bulk 1930-1938
Duke University Archives
Duke Artists Series records, 1931-2000
Duke University Archives
Duke University Union records, 1954-[ongoing]
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Arts, General (Box 1)
  - Arts, Calendars, 1980, 1990s (Box 1)
  - All-Star Concert Series, 1931-1949 (Box 1)
  - Artists Series, 1978- (Box 1)
  - Dance, 1943, 1965, 1979- (Box 1)
  - Dance: American Dance Festival, circa 1995- (Box 1)
  - Dance: Triangle Dance Guild, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Exhibits in art museums and galleries (Box 1)
  - Festivals, folklife (Box 1)
  - Medical Center Cultural Services (Box 1)
  - Music: general (Box 1)
  - Music: Chamber Arts Society, calendars and programs, circa 1960- (Box 1)
  - Music: Chamber Arts Society, clippings and histories (Box 1)
  - Music: Duke Madrigals, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Music: Duke Symphony & Duke Wind Symphony, circa 1966-1985 (Box 1)
  - Music: North Carolina Symphony, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Story-tellers' Ring in the Duke Forest, undated (Box 1)
  - Summer programs (Box 1)
  - Summer Program: Loblolly, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Synergetic Foundation for the Arts, circa 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Theater and film: American Musical Theater Center, circa 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Theater and film: Duke Stage Company, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Theater and film: World Premieres Festival, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Theater and film: The Opportunity / Robert F. Sommer, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Theater at Trinity College, circa 1910-1916 (Box 1)